Muhammad Salah Osman

Kyoto, Japan (080) 9751-4092 2022mm07@kuas.ac.jp Github | LinkedIn

Master's student at Kyoto University of Advanced Science in Japan, I have professional experience in software engineering developing Backend RESTful APIs and React Native mobile applications. I have strong research experience in developing Deep Learning algorithms for satellite data in the domain of water quality monitoring.

EDUCATION

Kyoto University of Advanced Science

Kyoto, Japan

MS in Engineering, Research in Satellite Remote Sensing

Sept. 2022 - Aug. 2024

Super KUAS-E Scholarship Recipient.

Deep Learning algorithms for water quality monitoring using satellite data.

Alexandria University

Alexandria, Egypt

BS in Computer and Systems Engineering, CGPA: 3.3

Sept. 2016 - Jul. 2021

Graduation Project: Deep learning system to generate music based on a given sentiment.

Hiroshima University

Hiroshima, Japan

Short-term cultural program

Aug. 2019 - Sept. 2019

Learned more about the Japanese language and the Japanese culture in Hiroshima.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Remote, Japan

Software Engineering Intern

Jun. 2023-Present

• Working remotely with a global team of engineers to implement backend and frontend features in Sansan's Bill One product using Kotlin and Reactjs.

Kyoto University of Advanced Science

Kyoto, Japan

Teaching Assistant

Sansan

Sept. 2022–Present

• Helping students with C Programming & grading assignments.

Rubikal, INC.

Alexandria, Egypt

Software Engineer

Dec. 2020-Aug. 2022

- Worked as a React Native Engineer on a food catering application.
- Developed Back End RESTful APIs using Ruby on Rails for several multinational clients.
- Participated in business decision-making from a technical design perspective.

Software Engineering Intern

Jul. 2020-Sept. 2020

Aug. 2021-Apr. 2022

Implemented an internal tool to handle food ordering inside the company using Ruby on Rails.

Chamber DS Freelancer React Native Mobile Developer

Remote

• Working as a React Native Developer on a product for athletes called InnerPro in the US.

Alphaya.com

Remote

Freelancer software developer

Apr. 2018–Aug. 2018

• KALILA project: Javascript application to compare multiple Arabic texts using DIFF and parsing algorithms.

Personal Projects

- 1D Convolutions and LSTM Deep Learning model for estimating Chl-a in the water from satellite data.
- Multi-view Knee MRI diagnoses classification using VGG16 Convolutional Neural Network.
- Implementing Artificial Neural Network in C language.
- PintOS: Implementation of a Unix Like operating system in C.
- Sotra: a Mobile Application for laundry requests and services build using a stack of PostgreSQL, Ruby on Rails, and React Native. The app was launched in Egypt and operated in the market for three months.
- Desktop mail server using Socket Programming on a LAN with file system storage built using Java.
- JDBC & DBMS implementation in Java.
- Dots and Boxes: an implementation of the game in pure C with GUI and MinMax with alpha-beta pruning algorithms.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages

Python, C/C++, JavaScript, TypeScript, Kotlin, Java, Ruby

Frameworks & Technologies

- Keras, Tensorflow, Deep Learning
- Numpy, Matplotlib, Pandas
- React Native, Redux, Cross Platform Mobile Development (Android & IOS)
- Ruby on Rails, RESTful APIs, Databases, Back-end development
- Docker, Containerization, AWS

General Skills

- OSx, Linux, Git
- Project Management, Finance, Economics
- Agile, JIRA, Testing & Debugging

Courses

- Coursera: Machine Learning (Andrew Ng)
- Coursera: Deep Learning Specialization
- Intro to Neural Computation (Dr. John A. Bullinaria)
- BerkeleyX: CS188 Artificial Intelligence (Edx)
- Finance for Non-Finance Professionals (Rice University)
- Udacity: App Marketing (Google)
- Microeconomics Principles (University of Illinois)

Achievements & Activities

- Second place best in category in Intel BASEF (2016).
- Second place in Hult Prize Alexandria on-campus for our environmental solution: Plantopia (2019).
- ACM Student Chapter Academic Head (2018).

Publications

- Muhammad Salah, Hiroto Higa, Joji Ishizaka, and Salem Ibrahim Salem, 1D Convolutional Neural Network-based Chlorophyll-a Retrieval Algorithm for Sentinel-2 MultiSpectral Instrument in Various Trophic States, Sens. Mater., Vol. 35, No. 11, 2023, p. 3743-3761.
- M. Salah, H. Higa, J. Ishizaka and S. I. Salem, "B1D-CNN: A Novel Convolution Neural Network-Based Chlorophyll-A Retrieval Algorithm for Sentinel-2 Data," IGARSS 2023 - 2023 IEEE International Geoscience and Remote Sensing Symposium, Pasadena, CA, USA, 2023, pp. 3950-3953, doi: 10.1109/IGARSS52108.2023.10281795.